HENRY HUYNH

11000 S. Eastern Ave. #2224, Henderson NV 89052 | Phone: 702-518-5265 | Email: henryhuynh.me@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

A dedicated and results-driven sales professional with many years of strong work ethics, responsibility and accountability. Very competitive when it comes to acquiring business, and competent in managing complex situations from a strategic and prudent perspective. Exceptional sales ability and strong interpersonal skills with positive and confident approach. Demonstrated ability to deliver results penetrating into new markets, expanding accounts, growing profits, and surpassing sales goals. Ability to take initiative and adapt quickly to changing priorities while meeting deadlines. Demonstrated ability to think strategically and analyze the needs of clients.

KEY SKILLS & STRENGTHS

- Relationship management
- High level of integrity and moral standards
- Strong organizational and time management skills
- Account penetration
- Excellent interpersonal, influencing, negotiation and closing skills
- Strategic planning
- Key account management
- Self-motivated with positive attitude
- Persistent

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Inspections Account Manager (10/2020 – Present)

Statewide Fire Protection - Las Vegas, NV

- Establish contact with potential qualified buyers of inspection services by diligently scheduling sales calls, following up on leads quickly after they're identified, and helping to execute outlined marketing strategies.
- Determine customer needs by conducting site surveys and reviewing findings with the appropriate customer personnel.
- Prepare and present effective proposals that offer solutions to customer life safety needs.
- Contribute to the pricing approach of inspection accounts.
- Maintain and report sales business plan and attend monthly sales call.
- Holds responsibility for understanding of assigned market and reporting business dynamics (market share, competition, top customers, top prospects, etc.) of assigned geographic area.
- Develop and maintain an active proposal pipeline to support the established sales business plan.
- Develop caring and enduring customer relationships that meet and exceed the expectations of the customers.
- Support other teams.
- Learn and follow the Operating code 100% of the time.
- Actively participate in the WSFP IMA program.

Online Marketing and Search Engine Optimization Consultant (02/2018 – 10/2020)

Self-employed – Henderson, NV

- Developed SEO strategies for clients by conducting keyword research and strategies, competitive analysis, domain authority, current rankings that contribute to a successful SEO campaign.
- Performed on-site and off-site search engine optimization for each client in order to increase their page rank on Google and YouTube

- Handled client relations by preparing comprehensive strategy updates, reports, and feedback
- Analyzed and stayed up to date on evolving SEO trends, practices, and guidelines

Commercial Account Manager (08/2015 – 02/2018)

OneSource Communications - Fort Worth, TX

- Consistently exceeded monthly sales quota
- Primary responsibility was developing and maintaining strong, long-lasting relationships with new and existing accounts
- Ensured revenue growth by developing and maintaining strong sales relationships
- Drove the entire sales process: target prospects, identify solutions, negotiate, and close sales
- Responsible for upselling voice, data and video services to existing and new customers, as well as the renewal, retention and win back of customers
- Developed and maintained relationships with internal stakeholders to achieve sales objectives

Personal Banker (09/2012 – 07/2015)

Bank of America - Reno, NV

- Responsible for identifying customer and small business banking needs, creating a valued added experience, recommending the best products, services and solutions, responding and providing highquality service to every customer during each meeting
- Leveraged performance metrics and sales reports to identify opportunities to meet/exceed performance
 expectations, increase sales interactions, drive revenue, and shift customers toward more high value
 relationships including account management
- Ensured a world class customer experience by taking personal responsibility to address customers' needs and making sure that the customer understands the solution

General Manager (2006 – 2012)

Saigon 88 Restaurant – Sparks, NV

- Responsible for Saigon 88 achieving "Best of Reno Award" for two consecutive years
- Implemented procedures to ensure excellent culinary and customer service, Saigon 88 was recognized with a 3.5 out of 5.0 stars from the Reno Gazette Journal
- Hired and trained both new and existing employees on providing and maintaining high-quality culinary and customer focus/experience through dependable teamwork
- Managed all aspects of food service operations: inventory control, food sanitation, quality control of food products, and profit and loss responsibility

Sales Representative (2002 – 2006)

AT&T Wireless - Reno, NV

- President's Club achiever, Top 4% in sales, all-expense paid trip to Hawaii
- Developed and managed new and existing accounts
- Prospected new business and closed sales utilizing cold calling and networking
- Proactively followed up with prospective customers
- Conducted demonstrations of telecom products and services
- Consistently met and exceeded monthly sales goals

EDUCATION

University of Nevada, Reno Bachelor's of Science in Business Administration